<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colton Barger on Colton</title>
    <link>https://www.cbarger.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colton Barger on Colton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cbarger.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing NHL Shot Data With a Streamlit Web App</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/nhl-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/nhl-web-app/</guid>
      <description>Overview The web application can be viewed here and the Github repository for this project can be seen here.
In this application, I take data that I obtained from Kaggle user Martin Ellis at this link and visualize shots made by 30 players from around the league. I narrowed the dataset down to the 30 players with the most shots due to the files being too large if every NHL player was included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting NHL Game Outcomes with ML and Why It&#39;s Difficult</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/nhl-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/nhl-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Here I collect data from 17 NHL seasons beginning with the 2005-2006 season and ending with the 2021-2022 season. I extract the data directly from nhl.com using web scraping techniques (although there are a ton of better sites to get game data from). I clean the data and extract features from each team&amp;rsquo;s individual performance. I calculate a rolling average/summary of multiple statistics for a few different timeframes and compare those to their opponent&amp;rsquo;s same stats for each game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis and Forecasting with ARIMA</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/arima_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/arima_modeling/</guid>
      <description>Summary ARIMA models are time series models often used in economics and finance to forecast the future. Here I talk a bit about ARIMA models in general and present an example of forecasting future populations gains of the US using ARIMA in Python.
The Jupyter notebook in which I perform the following analyses can be found on my GitHub here.
What is ARIMA, Exactly? ARIMA is an acronym describing a method of combined statistical techniques to model and predict time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of a Chess Games Dataset</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/chess-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/chess-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Summary I perform an exploratory data analysis of a dataset made up of chess games played on Lichess found here. There are over 20,000 games from 12,000+ players on lichess.org found in the dataset with which I try to answer questions such as
 How big of an advantage do players with the white pieces have, if any? How does rating affect the outcome of a game? Are there any players in the dataset with a suspiciously high winning rate?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Chutes &amp; Ladders Using Markov Chains</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/chutes-and-ladders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/chutes-and-ladders/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Chutes &amp;amp; Ladders, or Eels &amp;amp; Escalators for any Spongebob Squarepants fans like myself out there, is a game all about luck. The goal is to get to exactly the end of the 100-tile board by rolling a six-sided die. No over-shooting. If you happen to land at the base of a ladder, you may move up to the top of the ladder. If you are unfortunate enough to land on top of a slide, you go all the way to the bottom of the slide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Lost Ark Gold Prices off of g2g.com</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/g2g-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/g2g-scraping/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this project I develop a web scraper using python, selenium, and BeautifulSoup4 to collect data on gold prices for the MMORPG Lost Ark and display it in an online dashboard. The dashboard is compiled using plotly and dash, and then deployed to Heroku.
GitHub Repository For This Project
View the Dashboard For This Project
Features  Scrapes paginated data across 62 servers and 5 regions Displays the time series of gold prices in an interactive graph using dropdown bars Displays the time series of gold prices for every gold seller of Lost Ark  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotten Tomatoes Reviews NLP and Sentiment Analysis Using LSTM</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/rotten-tomatoes-sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/projects/rotten-tomatoes-sentiment/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this project I scrape movie reviews for the top 100 movies between 2000 and 2021 from Rotten Tomatoes (with the addition of Interstellar (2014)). After scraping the reviews, I apply Natural Language Processing (NLP) on the reviews dataset before training a Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) to attempt to perform sentiment analysis on further reviews. The model accurately predicted positive.negative reviews with 89% accuracy after all was said and done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Colton. I&amp;rsquo;m a person with many hobbies, some of which may not make sense to mix together. First and foremost, I love to learn. I received a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Physics from Penn State Behrend, a branch campus of Penn State, in 2019. Afterwards, I moved on to study applied mathematics at Bowling Green State University and graduated with a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in 2021. I keep my brain in check by taking random courses on Coursera (and sometimes finishing them), and doing analysis on datasets in my spare time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to contact me about anything: critiques, recruitment opportunities, invitations for friendship, etc.
Email: cbarger233@gmail.com
LinkedIn
GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
