<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Colton</title>
    <link>https://www.cbarger.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Colton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cbarger.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Lost Ark Gold Prices off of g2g.com</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/post/g2g-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/post/g2g-scraping/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this project I develop a web scraper using python, selenium, and BeautifulSoup4 to collect data on gold prices for the MMORPG Lost Ark and display it in an online dashboard. The dashboard is compiled using plotly and dash, and then deployed to Heroku.
GitHub Repository For This Project
View the Dashboard For This Project
Features  Scrapes paginated data across 62 servers and 5 regions Displays the time series of gold prices in an interactive graph using dropdown bars Displays the time series of gold prices for every gold seller of Lost Ark  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rotten Tomatoes Reviews Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/post/rotten-tomatoes-sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/post/rotten-tomatoes-sentiment/</guid>
      <description>Summary In this project I scrape movie reviews for the top 100 movies between 2000 and 2021 from Rotten Tomatoes (with the addition of Interstellar (2014)). After scraping the reviews, I apply Natural Language Processing (NLP) on the reviews dataset before training a Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) to attempt to perform sentiment analysis on further reviews. The model accurately predicted positive.negative reviews with 89% accuracy after all was said and done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of a Chess Games Dataset from Kaggle</title>
      <link>https://www.cbarger.com/post/chess-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cbarger.com/post/chess-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Summary I perform an exploratory data analysis of a dataset made up of chess games played on Lichess found here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
